LyricShow Player V0.8.8 Olympic Version 2008.08.15
English Edition Translator: ElecFerrari, YANZI7503

LyricShow Player, is a lyrics Synchronous music player, shows you the lyrics when playing music.

This is the version suit for SonyEricsson mobile phone with 240x320 screen, which supports Java MIDP2.0 and JSR75 File API.

LyricShow Player may supports media format such as mid/imy/amr/wav
/mp3/aac/wma/3gp/mp4. 
(defined by phone itself)

Besides, you can read E-books when listening. Furthermore, you can read E-books and rolling lyrics at the same time.

At start-up of Olympic Version, select "One World One Dream" means select English language, otherwise Chinese language.


*Keys of MPlayer 

Left SoftKey: Main menu
Right SoftKey: Switch playlists and lyrics 
5(short press): Media play/Pause/continue
5(long press): Replay current media

4(short press): Choose previous media
4(long press): Play previous media
6(short press): Choose next media
6(long press): Play next media
2(short press): Volume up
2(long press): Media forward
8(short press): Volume down
8(long press): Media backward

1: Local time, music time and progress
3: previous page of playlist
7: Media stop
9: To file broswer
*: Mute
#(short press): Next page of playlist
#(long press): Keys Lock/Unlock
0: Change play modes (in playlist), change max measure (in video play)
0(long press): switch 2 default skins

Green key: Send SMS
C key: Reverse screen
*+#: Illumination On/Off
When play videos: Right SoftKey to switch playlists and video-show.


*Keys of EReader

Left SoftKey: Main menu
Right SoftKey: Show/Hide lyrics
5: Media Play/Pause/Continue

4: Previous Page
6: Next Page
2: Previous line
8: Next line
1: Time, Page, Filename, Progress info
3: Auto Scroll
7: Media Stop
9: To file broswer
*: Mute
#(short press): Next char
#(long press): Keys lock/unlock
0: Change background colors

Green key: Send SMS
C key: Reverse screen
*+2: Volume up
*+3: Change fonts
*+4: Previous media
*+6: Next media
*+8: Volume down
*+#: Illumination on/off


*Player & Lyrics

(1)LyricShow Player starts from music player, press 9 to browse files. If you meet the security enquire, please choose "for session" (Always Allow).

(2)In music player, press 5 to play, 7 to stop. If the music has its lyric, press Right SoftKey to switch lyric and playlist. Attention, the lyric file (*.lrc) must be the same filename with its music, for example "abc.mp3" & "abc.lrc". Lyric file can be put in the same directory with its music, or put into folder c:/Other/lyricshow/lyrics/ or e:/lyricshow/lyrics/ . 

(3)Character set of lyric file (*.lrc) should be ANSI(GB2312), Unicode or UTF-8.

(4)Lyric file (*.lrc) for your favorite music can be created by yourself, or downloaded from some website. For example, www.lrcdb.org . Supports lrc flags "ti" (or "title"), "ar" (or "artist") and "offset".

(5)Supports LRD format. LRD is a package of lyric files. You can use LRD Maker to put all lyric files of a playlist into one LRD file (*.lrd). First please setup LRD file folder in Setitings.

(6)If you cancel all available paths of lrc and lrd, no lyrics will be loaded when music start.


*EBook Reader

(1)Press 9 to open ebooks (txt e.g.). Left SoftKey to show main menu, and Right SoftKey to show/hide lyric text. Press Green key while reading ebooks, text will be copy to SMS edit page.

(2)This version do NOT supports standard zip compress files.

(3)Character Set of ebook files should be ANSI(GB2312), Unicode(Suggest) or UTF-8. Calculates 256 bytes for one page.

(4)Max 32 user-define bookmarks for each book. Bookmark file will be saved automatically.

(5)"Recent Books" records the recent 15 reading books. 


*Playlists & Skins

(1)you can create/edit/delete/rename playlists, and the max size of each playlist is 500. Playlists will be saved automatically.

(2)There are two default skins. Alos allows to add extra skin files, save to c:/Other/lyricshow/skins/ or e:/lyricshow/skins/ .

Notes: This version supports Full Screen to show lyrics, but it needs new skins which provide full screen panel. Choose "Skin" in color settings means using a color which defined in skin configuration.


*Settings

(1)Language: after select a new language, restart application and apply new setting.

(2)Time: in order to show local time, please select time zone, such as China in "+8".

(3)Auto Screen Saver: should setup start time in "Settings".

(4)Auto Scroll of EReader: please setup speed of Auto Scroll also in "Settings".

(5)Auto Exit: in MPlayer or EReader, application auto exit if there is no operation in appointed time.
 
All settings become effective except language. All settings will be saved automatically.


*More Info

(1)After screen reversed, key function of 2/4/6/8 and stick key will be changed accordingly.

(3)All folders mentioned above, may be created by yourself, or go to "Settings" to create them.

(4)Please make sure Web/Wap settings of mobile phone is correct before call for internal Web/Wap Browser.


*Thanks & About

Thanks go to YANZI7503, ElecFerrari, comdin, snoopyhzy, and all friends who help in devlopments.

Special thanks: 0110.CN, Sun Microsystem, BenQ Mobile GmbH.

Thank you for using, any question or advice please feel free to contact me.
It is also welcome to translate & introduce this free software everywhere.

LyricShow Player is the 1st Winner of Student Category of Java Masters 2006.
Now there are versions for different mobile phones published. For instance, Siemens (BenQ-Siemens), SonyEricsson, Nokia and Motorola. 
Please visit http://hi.baidu.com/lyricshow2008 or contact me to get news or software.

Copyright (C) 2006-2008

Developer: Weijian Chen (Pan), from NKU & HIT, China.
E-mail: faterpan@yahoo.com.cn